{"name": "66C  2008-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The second term of an arithmetic sequence is 12, and the third term is 6. What is the first term?(Note: In an arithmetic sequence, consecutive terms differ by the same amount.)", "choices": {"A": "-12", "B": "-6", "C": "", "D": "6", "E": "18"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Let a function of 2 variables be defined by f(x,y) = xy - (x - y). What is the value of f(10,3)?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "17", "C": "23", "D": "37", "E": "43"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Kele work s at the high school concession stand to help raise money for the math team. Kele only uses 1\u00a2, 5\u00a2, 10\u00a2, and 25\u00a2 coins when making change. What is the least number of these coins needed to make change totaling 44\u00a2 ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "7", "D": "8", "E": "9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What is the perimeter, in centimeters, of  a rectangle with length 10 cm and width 5 cm?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "20", "C": "30", "D": "50", "E": "100"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. If x = -4, what is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "3", "D": "", "E": "11"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Which of the following is NOT a factor of 1,001 ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "7", "C": "11", "D": "13", "E": "17"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. The 16-member drama club needs to choose a student government representative. They decide that the representative, who will be chosen at  random, CANNOT be any of the 3 officers  of the club. What is the probability  that Adrian, who is a member of the club but NOT an officer, will be chosen?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. For what value of x is the equation 3(x - 6) + x = 30 true\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "12", "C": "9", "D": "6", "E": "3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Chenoa is working as a summer intern for a state senator running for reelection. She is in charge of ordering election signs. The cost of printing election signs includes a one-time fee of $15.00, plus $0.33 for each sign printed. Which of the following is the cost, in dollars, to print x signs?", "choices": {"A": "15.33x", "B": "15.00x + 0.33", "C": "4.95x", "D": "0.33x + 15.00", "E": "0.33x - 15.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Juanita purchased an automobile for a total of $14,000. She financed all of the $14,000 and started payments of $315 a month for 5 years. At the end of the 5-year period, how much more than the purchase price will Juanita have paid for her automobile?", "choices": {"A": "$980", "B": "$1,575", "C": "$2,205", "D": "$3,780", "E": "$4,900"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. 8x5 12x5 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "20x10", "B": "20x25", "C": "96x5", "D": "96x10", "E": "96x25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The expression is equal to:", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. On a real number line, point A is at -5.5 and is 7. 5 units from point B. What are the possible locations of B on the real number line?", "choices": {"A": "-13 and -2", "B": "-13 and 2", "C": "-13 and 13", "D": "13 and -2", "E": "13 and 2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. A data set contains 5 elements and has a mean of 6. Four of the elements are 1, 3, 7, and 8. Which of the following is the fifth element?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "11", "D": "13", "E": "17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The yearly net profit earned by the Atlas Baby Food Company for 1999 was $2,379,000, and the yearly net profit earned for 2001 was $2,426,000. If the yearly net profits increased linearly from 1999 through 2001, what was the yearly net profit earned for 2000 ?", "choices": {"A": "$2,105,050", "B": "$2,350,000", "C": "$2,400,000", "D": "$2,402,500", "E": "$2,425,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. On a map, the lengths of the sides of a triangular parcel of land are 3, 5, and 7 centimeters. The shortestside has an actual length of 410 meters. Which of the following is closest to the actual length, in meters, of the longest side?", "choices": {"A": "176", "B": "586", "C": "656", "D": "683", "E": "957"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. What is the slope-intercept form of 4x - y - 3 = 0?", "choices": {"A": "y = -4x - 3", "B": "y = -4x + 3", "C": "y = 3x - 4", "D": "y = 4x - 3", "E": "y = 4x + 3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. What is the value of | -8 | - | 7 - 43 |?", "choices": {"A": "-44", "B": "-28", "C": "28", "D": "44", "E": "58"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. In \u0394ABC, \u2220A measures greater than 22\u00b0 and \u2220B measures exactly 58\u00b0. Which of the following phrases best describes the measure of \u2220C?", "choices": {"A": "Greater than 100\u00b0", "B": "Less than 100\u00b0", "C": "Equal to 60\u00b0", "D": "Equal to 80\u00b0", "E": "Equal to 100\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. What is the greatest integer w that satisfies the inequality \\frac{w}{3}+1\">?", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": "24", "C": "25", "D": "26", "E": "28"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. You are designing a play mat for toy cars. An existing railroad track meets a straight road at an angle of 94\u00b0 to the road, as shown in the figure below. You are adding a new railroad track beyond and parallel to the existing track. What is the degree measure of the angle between the road and the new track, as indicated below?", "choices": {"A": "86\u00b0", "B": "88\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "92\u00b0", "E": "94\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In right triangle \u0394ABC shown below, D is the midpoint of AC. To the nearest 0.1 foot, what is the length of AD?", "choices": {"A": "2.5", "B": "3.5", "C": "5.0", "D": "12.5", "E": "25.0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Use the following information to answer questions 23-24.When Michelle defrosts frozen hamburger in her family's microwave, she enters the hamburger's weight, to the nearest 0.1 pound, and the microwave automatically sets the defrost time. Michelle defrosts 3 different amounts of frozen hamburger in her family's microwave and wonders if there is a relationship between the weights and corresponding microwave defrost times. She graphs the 3 weights and corresponding microwave defrost times in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, as shown below, and notices a linear relationship between these 3 points. She finds that an equation of the line through these 3 points is y = 420x + 10.How many seconds longer is the microwave's defrost time for 2.4 pounds of frozen hamburger than for 0.9 pounds of frozen hamburger?", "choices": {"A": "252", "B": "378", "C": "630", "D": "640", "E": "1,018"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Use the following information to answer questions 23-24.When Michelle defrosts frozen hamburger in her family's microwave, she enters the hamburger's weight, to the nearest 0.1 pound, and the microwave automatically sets the defrost time. Michelle defrosts 3 different amounts of frozen hamburger in her family's microwave and wonders if there is a relationship between the weights and corresponding microwave defrost times. She graphs the 3 weights and corresponding microwave defrost times in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, as shown below, and notices a linear relationship between these 3 points. She finds that an equation of the line through these 3 points is y = 420x + 10.According to Michelle's equation, about how many seconds would it take to defrost 8 ounces of frozen hamburger in her family's microwave?\uff08Note: 1 pound = 16 ounces)", "choices": {"A": "194", "B": "210", "C": "220", "D": "336", "E": "346"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. In the polygon below, all pairs of the 8 line segments that meet do so at right angles, and all the dimensions given are in inches. What is the area, in square inches, of the polygon?", "choices": {"A": "80", "B": "82", "C": "84", "D": "88", "E": "92"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Maria's 7-hour drive to college was 355 miles long. She averaged 45 miles per hour for the first 2 hours. Which of the following is closest to her average speed, in miles per hour, for the remainder of her drive?", "choices": {"A": "38", "B": "51", "C": "53", "D": "55", "E": "56"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. For all x, (x2 + 2x + 1)(x - 1) = ?", "choices": {"A": "x3 + x2 - x - 1", "B": "x3 + x2 + 3x + 1", "C": "x3 + 2x2 + x - 1", "D": "x3 + 2x2 + x + 1", "E": "x3 + 2x - 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. For \u2220A in \u0394ABC below, which of the following trigonometric expressions has value ?", "choices": {"A": "cos A", "B": "csc A", "C": "sec A", "D": "sin A", "E": "tan A"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Mark was responsible for buying yo-yos and tops to use as prizes for the school carnival. His receipt showed that he spent a total of $32.20 and that he bought 60 items. Yo-yos cost $0.65 each, and tops cost $0.25 each. How many yo-yos did.Mark buy to use as prizes for the school carnival?\uff08Note: There was no tax charged on the items because they were bought for a school.)", "choices": {"A": "19", "B": "21", "C": "30", "D": "39", "E": "43"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. The operation @ is defined as follows: a @ b = where a and b are real numbers and a \u2260 b. What is the value of (-2) @ (-6) ?", "choices": {"A": "-10", "B": "-8", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "10"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Nam is planning to make a cake using a recipe that calls for  cups of pecans. He has  cups of pecans in a canister. The amount of pecans in the canister is what fraction of the amount of pecans he needs for the recipe?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. As shown below, O is the center of a circle, AB is a diameter of the circle, C lies on the circle, AC = CB, and OB = 7 cm. What is the area, in square centimeters, of \u0394ABC?", "choices": {"A": "14", "B": "28", "C": "49", "D": "98", "E": "196"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Which of the following values of x is in the solution set of the equation x2 + 5x - 14 = 10?", "choices": {"A": "-24", "B": "-8", "C": "-7", "D": "-3", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. As shown in the figure below, a silo consists of a right circular cylinder with a hemisphere on top. The radius of the cylinder and of the hemisphere is 10 feet, and the height of the cylinder is 25 feet. Which of the following is closest to the volume, in cubic feet, of the silo?(Note: The volume of a right circular cylinder is given by \u03c0r2h, where r is the radius and h is the height. The volume of a hemisphere is given by , where r is the radius. )", "choices": {"A": "2,200", "B": "8,900", "C": "9,900", "D": "21,700", "E": "52,400"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. An isosceles trapezoid has an area of 35 square feet, a height of 5 feet, and one base that is 8 feet long. The other base must be how many feet long?", "choices": {"A": "1.75", "B": "4.5", "C": "6", "D": "15", "E": "30"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. What is the slope of the line through the points (-4, 1) and (-6, -3) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "-7", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Points A, B, and C are vertices of an equilateral triangle Point A, B, and D are collinear points, with B between A and D. What is the measure of \u2220CBD?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "60\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0", "E": "120\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. The decimal representation of  repeats and can be written as 0.857142857142\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7. What is the 100th digit to the right of the decimal point in this decimal representation?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Points A(-3, 0) , B(0, 3), and C(3, 0) lie in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. If ABCD is a square, then what is the length, in coordinate units, of CD ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "9", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The graph of the equation xy = 8 is reflected across the x-axis in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. Which of the following is an equation of the reflection?", "choices": {"A": "xy = -8", "B": "xy = 8", "C": "x | y | = 8", "D": "| xy | = 8", "E": "| x | y = -8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. The figure below shows an example in which AB and DE are perpendicular to BD, and AE and BD intersect at C: Which of the following statements is true about any such figure?", "choices": {"A": "ABDE", "B": "BCCD", "C": "BD bisects AE", "D": "\u25b3ABC \u25b3EDC", "E": "\u25b3ABC and \u25b3EDC are similar triangles."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44.The senior class at Figg High School is sponsoring a fund-raiser to raise $1,250.00 for a graduation celebration. They can choose 1 of the 2 fund-raising options listed below.Candy Bar option: After paying a start-up fee of $15.00, the senior class can purchase candy bars for $0.38 each and sell them for $1.00 each.Photo Prints option: After paying a start-up fee of $25.00, the senior class can sell photo prints at prom. The film and flash for the camera cost $1.00 per print. The senior class will sell each print for $3.00.For the Photo Prints option, at least how many prints must be sold to cover the start-up fee for the fund-raiser?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "9", "C": "12", "D": "13", "E": "25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44.The senior class at Figg High School is sponsoring a fund-raiser to raise $1,250.00 for a graduation celebration. They can choose 1 of the 2 fund-raising options listed below.Candy Bar option: After paying a start-up fee of $15.00, the senior class can purchase candy bars for $0.38 each and sell them for $1.00 each.Photo Prints option: After paying a start-up fee of $25.00, the senior class can sell photo prints at prom. The film and flash for the camera cost $1.00 per print. The senior class will sell each print for $3.00.There are 510 students in the senior class at Figg High School. Abram suggests that instead of selling something, each senior donate $3.00 toward the goal. If 80% of the senior class donates $3.00, by what percent, to the nearest whole percent of the goal, would the class fall short of the goal?", "choices": {"A": "1%", "B": "2%", "C": "3%", "D": "4%", "E": "5%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 42-44.The senior class at Figg High School is sponsoring a fund-raiser to raise $1,250.00 for a graduation celebration. They can choose 1 of the 2 fund-raising options listed below.Candy Bar option: After paying a start-up fee of $15.00, the senior class can purchase candy bars for $0.38 each and sell them for $1.00 each.Photo Prints option: After paying a start-up fee of $25.00, the senior class can sell photo prints at prom. The film and flash for the camera cost $1.00 per print. The senior class will sell each print for $3.00.The senior class chose the Candy Bar option and met their fund-raising goal. They must have sold a minimum of how many candy bars?", "choices": {"A": "1,978", "B": "2,041", "C": "2,259", "D": "3,250", "E": "3,329"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The graph in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below shows   for values of x such that 0 \u2264 x \u2264 6. The x-coordinates of points A, B, and C are 0, 3, and 6, respectively. What is the area of \u0394ABC, in square coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. In \u0394FGH below, FG is 14 feet long. To the nearest tenth of a foot, how many feet long is GH ?(Note: The law of sines states that for a triangle with sides of length a, b, and c opposite \u2220A, \u2220B, and \u2220C, respectively, ).(Note: sin 45\u00b0 \u2248 0.707, sin 63\u00b0 \u2248 0.891, sin 72\u00b0 \u2248 0. 951)", "choices": {"A": "9.9", "B": "10.4", "C": "12.5", "D": "13.1", "E": "13.3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. When using the quadratic formula, Monali found that an equation had solutions x =, where a is a positive real number. Which of the following expressions gives Monali's solutions as complex numbers?", "choices": {"A": "5 \u00b1 1ai", "B": "5 \u00b1 3ai", "C": "5 \u00b1 6ai", "D": "5 \u00b1 9ai", "E": "5 \u00b1 12ai"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the figure below, the circle with center O has a radius of 7 inches and the measure of AB is 80\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220BAO?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "50\u00b0", "D": "60\u00b0", "E": "80\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Tamas is 35 feet away from the base of a vertical flagpole on level ground. He sees the top of the flagpole at an angle of inclination of 40\u00b0. About how many feet higher than Tamas's eye level is the top of the flagpole?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "35 cos 40\u00b0", "D": "35 sin 40\u00b0", "E": "35 tan 40\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what are the coordinates of the center of the circle whose equation is x2 - 6x + y2 + 4y + 12 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "(-3, 2)", "B": "(-2, -3)", "C": " (-2, 3)", "D": "(3, -2)", "E": "(3, 2)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Stephanie has a rectangular graph 10 inches wide and 8 inches high that she needs to paste into a lab report for her science class. Stephanie will use a photocopy machine repeatedly to reduce the size of her graph. With each reduction, the width and height will each be reduced to 80% of what they each were. What is the minimum number of reductions using the photocopy machine that will allow the graph to fit in a space 3.5 inches high?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. If det = ad - bc, then det =?", "choices": {"A": "ad - bc", "B": "-ad + bc", "C": "ab - dc", "D": "-ab + bc", "E": "-ab - dc"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. In the figure below, all 9 circles are congruent and, each circle is tangent to each circle adjacent to it. Each circle, except the middle circle, is tangent to at least 1 side of the square. The circumference of each circle is 16\u03c0 centimeters. What is the length, in centimeters, of each side of the square?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "24", "C": "12", "D": "48\u03c0", "E": "24\u03c0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Nolan has 20 collectible stamps. He paid $43.75 foreach stamp 3 years ago. The stamps are currently valued at $51.85 each. How much more must the average value per stamp rise for the combined value of these 20 stamps to be exactly $300.00 more than Nolan paid for them?", "choices": {"A": "$15.41", "B": "$14.60", "C": "$10.22", "D": "$8.10", "E": "$6.90"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. In the figure below, the circles centered at P and Q intersect at A and B, and points P, X, Y, and Q are collinear. The lengths of PB,  QB and XY are 9, 12, and 2 units, respectively. What is the length, in units, of PQ?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "16", "C": "17", "D": "19", "E": "21"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A parabola with vertex (3, 7) and axis of symmetry x = 3 crosses the x-axis at (3 + , 0). At what other point, if any, does the parabola cross the x-axis?", "choices": {"A": "(3 - , 0)", "B": "(-3 -, 0)", "C": "(-3 +, 0)", "D": "No other point", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. When x \u2260 5 and x \u2260 -5, is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. An angle with measure \u03c6 is shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The angle with measure \u0444 has the positive x-axis as one side and has the portion of the line y = x shown as its other side. What is the value of sin \u03a6?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The amount of money, A dollars, in a savings account after t years is given by A = P + Prt, where P dollars is the amount of money in the account originally and r is the rate of simple interest. Which of the following expressions gives P in terms of A, r, and t?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "A - rt"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Consider the equation , where a and b are positive real numbers. What is b in terms of a?", "choices": {"A": "16a", "B": "9a", "C": "4a", "D": "3a", "E": "2a"}, "correct": "A"}]}